Electronic Arts Inc.  
Privacy and Cookie Policy  

Your privacy is important to EA and we take our responsibility of caring for it seriously. This policy describes how Electronic Arts Inc. ("EA") processes the personal information we collect about you when you use our products and services or when you attend live events hosted by or in connection with EA (collectively, "Services" or "EA Services"). In some cases, our subsidiaries may be considered data controllers, either together with EA or by themselves.  
  
TABLE OF CONTENTS  
  
1\. Information We Collect  
2\. How We Collect Your Information  
3\. How We Use Your Information  
4\. Who May Receive Your Information  
5\. Where We Hold Your Information  
6\. How We Protect Your Information  
7\. Children  
8\. Your Choices and Controls  
9\. Third-Party Services  
10\. Information for California Residents  
11\. Changes to Our Policy  
12\. Contact Us  
13\. Right to Contact a Data Protection Authority  

1\. Information We Collect  
  
The information we collect depends on what Services you use and how you use them.  
  
A. Information You Give Us Directly  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We collect information that you give us directly, such as when you create an EA Account, set up security questions, make purchases, or contact EA Help.  
\------------------------------------  
  
We collect information that you provide us, such as:  
  
\- Your EA Account information, including your email address, username, real name, country, date of birth, telephone number and password;  
\- Security questions and answers;  
\- Information you provide in response to surveys about our Services;  
\- Information you provide when seeking help from us, such as your name, telephone number, and records (including call recordings) of the issues you experience; and  
\- Billing information, such as your name, payment card number, payment account details, and shipping address.  
  
B. Information You Provide When Playing Online  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: When you play online, we may collect information about your gaming profile, your gameplay, or your use of social features.  
\------------------------------------  
  
When you use our social features, any text, audio, visual, and/or other electronic communications information that you disclose may be read, copied, collected, or used by other players and EA, and may become publicly available and/or may be processed by EA for the purposes described in Section 2(D): Anti-Cheat, Inappropriate Content, and Fraud Prevention Technologies. Please make sure your privacy settings and choices in the features you use reflect your preferences.  
  
When you play our online games, your in-game profile information, gameplay, and statistics are collected and some may be visible in-game, as well as visible to players outside the game in other EA Services, such as RaceNet. In some of our titles, we may record your gameplay and replay it to other players in-game and/or make it visible to other players outside the game in other EA Services. Leaderboards may also be available to view by other players outside the game in other EA Services. In competitive game modes, we may record your gameplay, and your controller button inputs, and replay these together with your in-game profile information and game statistics to other players in-game and at live EA or partner events.  
  
C. Other Information We Collect When You Use Our Services  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We may collect other information when you use our Services, such as information about your device, hardware and software information, IP address, or browser information.  
\------------------------------------  
  
We may collect other information automatically when you use our Services, such as:  
  
\- IP address;  
\- Information about your device, hardware, and software, such as your hardware identifiers, mobile device identifiers (like Apple Identifier for Advertising \[IDFA\], or Android Advertising ID \[AAID\]), platform type, settings and components, EA software and updates you have installed, and the presence of required plugins;  
\- Approximate geolocation data (derived from IP or device settings);  
\- Browser information, including your browser type and the language preference;  
\- Referring and exit pages, including pages viewed and other interactions with web content;  
\- Details about what Services you purchase or obtain, and your use of them;  
\- Device event information, including crash reports, request and referral URLs, and system activity details (e.g., whether you encountered an error playing our games or lost Internet access); and  
\- Other information (such as your likeness) that you may provide as part of your participation in live events.  
  
We also may collect and store information locally on your device, using mechanisms like cookies, browser web storage (including HTML 5), and application data caches.  
  
D. Information Provided to Us by Third Parties  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We may receive information about you from third parties, such as Sony, Microsoft, Nintendo, Google, mobile platforms, or third-party authenticators that you use to sign in to our Services.  
\------------------------------------  
  
We may receive information about you contained in third-party user accounts when you use EA online Services on or through third-party gaming platforms, such as those listed below. This information is provided to EA as part of establishing or linking an EA Account, which is necessary to access EA’s online services. We may also receive information from the third-party gaming platforms that you use for the purpose of delivering or analyzing the performance of EA marketing. Your use of EA online Services through these third parties indicates your agreement for the transfer of this information. Examples of information we receive when creating EA Accounts for our recently released titles are provided below. We never receive your credit card number or other financial information from these third parties as part of establishing or linking an EA Account.  
  
\- PlayStation®3 system, PlayStation®4 system, & PlayStation®5 console. Sony provides information from your account for PlayStation™Network such as your Online ID, email address, country, language, friend list, date of birth, and certain preferences.  
  
\- Xbox network. Microsoft provides information such as your Gamertag, email address, country, language, friend list, date of birth, and certain preferences.  
  
\- Wii / Wii U / Nintendo Switch™. Nintendo provides (as applicable to the device you have) information such as your Mii character, nickname, Nintendo Network ID, Nintendo Account, country, language, friend list, and certain preferences.  
  
Social Gaming Platforms. When you use third-party social gaming platforms (such as Discord or Twitch) and link your EA Account, we may receive information associated with your account on those platforms. Please review the notices presented to you when linking your accounts for details on the information EA receives.  
  
Mobile Platforms. If you play or purchase our games on your mobile device or tablet, we receive information about you from the app stores and other mobile platform providers. This information may include your username or device ID and the fact that you made a purchase, as applicable, but does not include any financial information. Some of our mobile platforms may send information to us that you authorize them to provide. Our mobile games also may request additional personal information from you, such as push notification tokens or contact list, however, we will collect this information only if you provide us with permission.  
  
Other Third Parties  
  
We may receive information from other third parties, like Facebook or Apple Game Center, when you use these services with our games. We may also receive information about you when other players choose to share their contact lists with us or from publicly-available websites.  
  
E. Legal Basis for Processing  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: Depending on where you reside, we may rely on different legal bases to process your information.  
\------------------------------------  
  
Our legal basis for processing your personal information varies depending on the type of information we collect, the context in which we collect it as well as on your country of residence, as indicated when you are setting up your EA Account or, when not signed into an EA Account, your location as determined by your IP address and/or your device registration country.  
  
If you are a resident of the European Economic Area (EEA) or of a jurisdiction where similar legal requirements may apply such as Brazil, Switzerland, and the United Kingdom, we rely on a number of legal bases to process information about you. We will process information about you where we have your consent, where we have a legitimate interest to do so, where the processing is necessary for the performance of a contract with you, and/or where we have a legal obligation to process your information. For example, we typically rely on:  
  
\- consent when placing cookies on your device on the web (through our cookie consent manager) to send you email marketing, or to deliver third party targeted advertising to you on our Services;  
\- our legitimate interests to process your information when providing you with customer service support, to serve targeted EA marketing of our Services, or for fraud prevention and security purposes; and  
\- on contractual necessity to process information when you create an EA Account or otherwise use our Services to enable us to provide you with our Services.  
  
If you are a resident in a territory where our legitimate interests mentioned above are not recognized as a lawful basis under applicable law, we will identify and use other appropriate lawful bases to process your personal information such as contractual necessity or your consent.  
  
2\. How We Collect Your Information  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We use various technologies to deliver and measure the effectiveness of our Services, to serve advertisements, and to enhance your player experience. These technologies include cookies and similar technologies, as well as analytics, advertising, anti-cheat, and anti-fraud technologies.  
\------------------------------------  
  
We and third parties use technologies described below to collect information to deliver our Services.  
  
A. Cookies and Similar Technologies  
  
Cookies are small text files stored on your Internet browser. We and our third-party partners use cookies and similar tracking technologies to help us understand things like what web pages, features, or ads you view and what games you play. This information helps us keep track of your shopping cart, measure the effectiveness of our advertising, make sure you don't see the same ad repeatedly, and otherwise enhance your experience. Please refer to Section 8: Your Choices and Controls for information on how to manage your cookie preferences.  
  
We may use tracking pixels or clear GIFs to collect information about your use of our Services and your response to our marketing emails. We use Internet log files (which contain technical data such as your IP address) to monitor traffic on our Services, troubleshoot technical problems, detect and prevent fraud, and enforce our User Agreement.  
  
We also use Analytics, Advertising, Anti-Cheat, and Anti-Fraud technologies in our Services. These technologies may utilize the same cookies or similar mechanisms as further described below.  
  
B. Analytics Technologies  
  
We use internal and third-party analytics technologies to collect information about how you use our Services, your computer or device and the health of our Services.  
  
For instance, we may collect and store data from your computer or device when you use our Services. This information includes technical and related information about your computer, device, and operating and/or network systems (such as IP Address and device identifiers); information about your engagement with certain features and services; gameplay and usage statistics; as well as system interactions and peripheral hardware. We may also collect and store data from your device to create probabilistic identifiers for the purposes of analyzing the services accessed by our players across devices. If you play a game offline without connecting to the Internet, this data will be stored on your device and transmitted to us when your device connects to the Internet. If you participate in online Services, we may also collect, use, store, transmit and publicly display your personal and/or statistical data regarding your game play (including scores, rankings and accomplishments), or identify content that is created and shared by you with other players.  
  
Third-party analytics technologies integrated into our Services may (including SDK \[Software Development Kit\] and API \[Application Program Interface\] integrations) combine the information they collect in connection with your use of EA's Services with information they have independently collected over time and/or across different platforms. Many of these companies collect and use information pursuant to their own privacy policies. A list of third-party analytics companies that operate in our Services as well as how to opt-out to the extent applicable can be found at privacyappendix.ea.com.  
  
C. Ad Serving Technologies  
  
Some of our Services employ ad serving technologies that use cookies, clear GIFs, web beacons, tracking pixels, SDK, API, and other similar technologies to deliver offers and advertising to you within EA Services as well as on third-party platforms and sites, and to measure the performance of our advertising campaigns. Some of these technologies can sync or connect behavior across different websites, mobile apps and devices to tailor offers and advertising to your interests. For instance, you may be presented with an offer for a game we think you might enjoy. Or, if you express interest in a game, you may receive an advertisement later for that game or similar Services on EA or third-party sites. Other in-game advertising technologies enable offers to be temporarily uploaded to your game, web browser, or mobile device and later replaced while you are online.  
  
These technologies collect and use information so we can serve appropriate offers and advertising to you, to measure effectiveness and distribution of these offers and advertising, and to understand how users interact with our Services. In addition to identifiers and certain information listed in Section 1(C): Other Information We Collect When You Use Our Services above, this information may include:  
  
\- Advertisements served and the location of the ad;  
\- Length of time an advertisement was visible;  
\- Domain type, IP address, size of the advertisement;  
\- Your interaction, if any, with the ad; and  
\- Advertisement response.  
  
Third-party advertising companies may combine the information collected in the context of delivering an offer to you via our Services with other information they have independently collected over time and/or across different websites. Many of these companies collect and use information pursuant to their own privacy policies. A list of ad serving companies that operate their own networks on our Services, their privacy notices, as well as how to opt-out to the extent applicable can be found at privacyappendix.ea.com.  
  
To learn more about some of these ad networks' practices, or to opt-out of third-party targeted advertising, you can also visit www.networkadvertising.org, www.aboutads.info/choices, youradchoices.ca, or www.youronlinechoices.eu. Note that opting-out does not mean you won't see ads; rather, it means that the advertising you see may not be as relevant to you.  
  
D. Anti-Cheat, Inappropriate Content, and Fraud Prevention Technologies  
  
We strive to provide a safe and fair gaming environment for all players. When you use our Services, we or third parties may use cookies and similar technologies, collect data about or from your machine or device, which may include a machine "fingerprint" or "hash" of your machine components, and gather other evidence about your gameplay, machine state, or participation in our Services for fraud prevention, security, cheat detection, and authentication purposes. We may also monitor publicly-available information, third-party sites, and/or use anti-cheat technology within our Services, including automated anti-fraud and abuse algorithms. If you believe your access to our games and/or Services was blocked by this technology in error, please contact us at EA Help (help.ea.com).  
  
We may also monitor, record, review, and retain voice or text communications, and other user-generated Content ("UGC", as defined in our User Agreement at https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/WEBTERMS/US/en/PC2/), in our Services for purposes of moderating inappropriate Content that violate our policies (like our Positive Play Charter at https://www.ea.com/commitments/positive-play/charter). Moderation includes detecting, investigating and removing inappropriate UGC, as well as potentially sanctioning those players whose activities we find as violating our policies.  
  
3\. How We Use Your Information  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We use your information to operate our Services, to improve your game experience, to provide you customer support, to serve and measure the effectiveness of advertising, and to personalize our communications with you.  
\------------------------------------  
  
We use your personal information, both individually and combined together, in the following ways.  
  
To operate our business and to enhance and personalize your game experience, including to:  
  
\- Operate, analyze, improve, and develop our games and Services;  
\- Undertake research and analysis to develop and demonstrate our technology, and to better understand our players;  
\- Populate online leaderboards and enable online matchmaking;  
\- Provide replays to you and other players via spectator modes;  
\- Help you find your friends or tell your friends about an EA game or Service;  
\- Facilitate sharing on social networks;  
\- Manage and serve advertising in-game and on third-party platforms;  
\- Measure the effectiveness and distribution of advertising, including understanding who engages with our Services and how they interact with our Services;  
\- Measure the health of our Services;  
\- Detect security incidents, protect against malicious, deceptive, fraudulent or illegal activity, and prosecute those responsible for that activity;  
\- Set up and maintain accounts for which you register;  
\- Provide game experiences that you may like, including personalizing your game experience;  
\- Set up and facilitate loyalty programs;  
\- Facilitate your gameplay on multiple devices and/or platforms, as applicable;  
\- Identify, fix, and troubleshoot bugs or functionality errors;  
\- Provide software updates;  
\- Authenticate and activate your games and save game-play data, including progress;  
\- Facilitate competitions and contests;  
\- Perform audits, transactions, and other compliance activities;  
\- Adhere to your preferences and to deliver content;  
\- Help keep our Services safe and fair, including for such purposes as described in Section 2(D) and to further our Content Moderation and Enforcement (https://www.ea.com/commitments/positive-play/content-moderation);  
\- Resolve disputes, investigate and help curb fraud and illegal behavior, comply with the law, and enforce our agreements and policies; and  
\- Other purposes you consent to, are notified of, or are otherwise disclosed to you when you provide personal information.  
  
To provide you support, including to:  
  
\- Help identify and troubleshoot problems with your account or Services;  
\- Facilitate surveys or questionnaires;  
\- Communicate with you and respond to your specific requests or questions; and  
\- Manage and send you confirmations and important information about your account, Services, purchases, subscriptions, and warranties.  
  
To personalize our communications with you, including to:  
  
\- Provide you with relevant EA content, recommendations, information or offers; and  
\- Provide you with Service updates.  
  
Retention. We retain the information we collect for as long as necessary to provide our Services, and we may retain that information beyond that period if necessary for legal, operational, or other legitimate reasons.  
  
Where possible, we may also de-identify, anonymize, or aggregate the information we collect, or collect it in a way that does not directly identify you. We may use and share such information as necessary for our business purposes and as permitted by applicable law.  
  
4\. Who May Receive Your Information  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We may disclose your personal information to the categories of recipients we describe in this section, such as to provide our Services and to deliver advertisements.  
\------------------------------------  
  
Service providers. Vendors and other service providers that help us operate our business and provide you with Services may receive your personal information. We require that any service provider processing your personal information only do so on our behalf and for purposes consistent with this policy, such as the purposes described in Section 3: How We Use Your Information.  
  
Business partners. We may provide personal information to business partners with whom we jointly offer Services. These partners include the companies that provide the platform on which you play our games, such as Sony (PlayStation®4 system or PlayStation®5 console), Microsoft (Xbox), or others.  
  
Affiliates and subsidiaries. We may disclose personal information to other companies in which we have an ownership interest as necessary for the purposes outlined in this policy.  
  
Advertising partners. Through our Services, we may allow third-party advertising partners to use technologies and other tracking tools to collect information regarding your use of EA's Services and your device (such as your IP address, mobile identifiers, pages visited, location, browser information, time of day). We also may share information relating to your device and your use of our Services with our third-party advertising partners so they may deliver targeted advertisements to you when you visit third-party services and websites within their networks. This practice is commonly referred to as "interest-based advertising," "online behavioral advertising," or "targeted advertising."  
  
Please refer to Section 2(C): Ad Serving Technologies for more detail regarding online advertising, as well as Section 8: Your Choices and Controls regarding your relevant choices and controls.  
  
Disclosures to protect us or others. We may access, preserve, and disclose any information we store associated with you to external parties if we, in good faith, believe doing so is required or appropriate to: comply with law enforcement or national security requests and legal process, such as a court order or subpoena; protect your, our or others' rights, property, or safety; enforce our policies or contracts; collect amounts owed to us; or assist with an investigation or prosecution of suspected or actual illegal activity. In particular, if we receive a report that you have violated our policies (like our Positive Play Charter at https://www.ea.com/commitments/positive-play/charter), we may disclose that report and other relevant information to the platform on which you play our games.  
  
Disclosure in the event of merger, sale, or other asset transfer. In the event of a reorganization, divestiture, merger, sale, or bankruptcy, we may transfer all information we collect to the relevant third party and will obtain your consent to do so if required by law or contract.  
  
Third-party plugins. When third-party technologies or social tools are integrated into our Services, those third parties may collect information about your use of our Services. An example is the Facebook "Like" button.  
  
In certain instances (such as on our websites), our Services incorporate YouTube videos and use YouTube API Services. This integration is subject to the YouTube Terms of Service (https://www.youtube.com/t/terms), and may result in the collection of your personal information by Google according to the Google Privacy Policy (http://www.google.com/policies/privacy). If you have authorized us to receive your YouTube or other Google information, such as through logging in to our Services through your Google Account, you may manage your authorization (including revocation) through the Google Security Settings (https://security.google.com/settings/security/permissions). You may also have other rights with respect to your personal information that we have collected, as described in Section 8: Your Choices and Controls.  
  
Cross-platform sharing. Some of our games allow you to connect and play with friends and members of a game's community, regardless of what platform they play on. For example, someone on an Xbox could join a match with a player who is using a PlayStation®4 system or PlayStation®5 console. We call this ability to match players across platforms "Cross-Play." When Cross-Play is enabled and you play with someone on another platform, that other platform may receive your platform's ID (such as Xbox Gamertag, or Online ID of your account for PlayStation™Network) along with other information necessary to enable Cross-Play. In addition, we may provide information regarding your use of Cross-Play features to the platform on which you play our games. You can change your Cross-Play preferences by visiting the game's or your platform's settings menus.  
  
Some of our games may also allow you to continue progress on a game between platforms, as well as enable the ability for your purchases on one platform to be available on another platform. We will share your information with platforms to the extent necessary to enable these features.  
  
Other platforms receiving your information may include Sony (PlayStation®4 system or PlayStation®5 console), Microsoft (Xbox), Nintendo (Nintendo Switch), Valve (Steam), Epic, and additional platforms as they become available for these features. Your information received by these platforms may be subject to their respective privacy notices.  
  
With your consent. We may disclose your information to other recipients with your express consent, unless otherwise described above. For example, you may agree to us sharing your information with a certain company or organization to hear about their products, services, or promotions, or if you tell us that you want to link your EA Account with another company’s services. These recipients will process the information you agree to share according to their respective privacy notices.  
  
5\. Where We Hold Your Information  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We store and process your information in the United States and other countries where we operate. When we do this, we utilize technical, physical, and administrative safeguards to meet data transfer requirements set by various privacy laws, such as the European General Data Protection Regulation.  
\------------------------------------  
  
When you access EA Services, including when available on third-party platforms, your personal information is generally collected by EA directly and processed in the United States. Personal information we collect may be subsequently stored and processed for the purposes set out in this Privacy and Cookie Policy in the United States or any other country in which EA, its subsidiaries, or third-party agents operate. By consenting to the transfer of your personal data outside of your country of residence, you acknowledge that your personal information may be transferred to recipients in the United States and other countries that may not offer the same level of privacy protection as the laws in your country of residence or citizenship.  
  
EA's privacy practices comply with the Asia-Pacific Economic Cooperation Cross-Border Privacy Rules System (APEC CBPR). The APEC CBPR System provides a framework for organizations to ensure protection of personal information transferred among participating APEC economies. More information about the APEC framework is available here: https://cbprs.org.  
  
Electronic Arts Inc., and its U.S.-based subsidiaries ("EA Inc. US"), complies with the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (EU-U.S. DPF), the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework (Swiss-U.S. DPF) as set forth by the U.S. Department of Commerce. EA Inc. US has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the EU-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (EU-U.S. DPF Principles) with regard to the processing of personal data received from the European Union in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF and from the United Kingdom (and Gibraltar) in reliance on the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF. EA Inc. US has certified to the U.S. Department of Commerce that it adheres to the Swiss-U.S. Data Privacy Framework Principles (Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles) with regard to the processing of personal data received from Switzerland in reliance on the Swiss-U.S. DPF. If there is any conflict between the terms in this privacy policy and the EU-U.S. DPF Principles and/or the Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles, the Principles shall govern. To learn more about the Data Privacy Framework (DPF) program, and to view our certification, please visit https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/. The EA Inc. US entities subject to the DPF Principles are available at https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/list.  
  
EA Inc. US is responsible for the processing of personal data it receives, under the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and Swiss-U.S. DPF, and subsequently transfers to a third party acting as an agent on its behalf. EA Inc. US complies with the EU-U.S. DPF and Swiss-U.S. DPF Principles for all onward transfers of personal data from the EU, UK, and Switzerland, including the onward transfer liability provisions.  
  
The Federal Trade Commission has jurisdiction over EA Inc. US’ compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF. In certain situations, EA Inc. US may be required to disclose personal data in response to lawful requests by public authorities, including to meet national security or law enforcement requirements.  
  
In compliance with the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF, EA Inc. US commits to refer unresolved complaints concerning our handling of personal data received in reliance on the EU-U.S. DPF, the UK Extension to the EU-U.S. DPF, and the Swiss-U.S. DPF to TRUSTe, an alternative dispute resolution provider based in the United States. If you do not receive timely acknowledgment of your DPF Principles-related complaint from us, or if we have not addressed your DPF Principles-related complaint to your satisfaction, please visit U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request) for more information or to file a complaint. The services of TrustArc are provided at no cost to you.  
  
Under certain conditions, more fully described on the Data Privacy Framework website (https://www.dataprivacyframework.gov/), you may be entitled to invoke binding arbitration when other dispute resolution procedures have been exhausted.  
  
6\. How We Protect Your Information  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We use a range of security measures to secure and protect your information.  
\------------------------------------  
  
Security of your information is a priority at EA and we take a range of technical and organizational measures to help protect it, including encryption of sensitive information. Even so, please be aware that no security measure is perfect. Thus we cannot guarantee the security of your information at all times. You should always be diligent when it comes to the protection of your personal information. Learn more about EA Security at https://www.ea.com/security.  
  
7\. Children  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We strive to provide age-appropriate experiences for children. Depending on the age of the child accessing our online Services, parents or guardians may need to provide permission to enable their child to access certain online features of our Services.  
\------------------------------------  
  
Although the majority of EA Services are intended for adults, EA recognizes the importance of protecting the privacy of children who may access our Services online. We strive to ensure that children who access our Services receive age-appropriate experiences by employing data minimization, privacy by design, and default practices. We consider the best interests of children when determining the age-appropriate experience they receive and take into account the developmental maturity of children of different ages. When children reach the age of majority in their country or territory, they may receive the adult experience.  
  
When players identify themselves as being children under the minimum age of digital consent guidelines set by the law of individual countries or territories, we will:  
  
(1) obtain consent from parents for the use of their children's personal information, when required by applicable law. For example, we allow parents to create a child EA Account on certain Services, and with parental consent EA will collect and use certain children’s personal information to manage a child EA Account;  
  
(2) disable features in certain Services that could allow a child to share information that directly identifies them, unless a parent has provided relevant consent to us or the third-party platform on which their child is playing. For example, we will respect third-party (console) parental controls as they apply to game features that could allow a child to provide personal information in online or multiplayer games (such as through chat or user generated content);  
  
(3) collect and use certain information for limited purposes only. For example, we may send local in-app notifications, which do not rely on collecting personal information. Also, persistent device identifiers like IP address or advertising device identifier may be collected to support our internal operations, such as:  
  
\- Delivering the Services;  
\- Maintaining or analyzing the functionality of the Service;  
\- Serving contextual ads or frequency capping;  
\- Protecting the security or integrity of the user of Service; or  
\- Legal or regulatory compliance;  
  
(4) not condition a child's participation in an activity (such as gaming contests) on the disclosure of more personal information than is reasonably necessary to participate in the activity. With certain Service-related activities, we may not permit children to participate at all, even if we have consent; and  
  
(5) offer parental controls and choices. If you are a parent or guardian and wish to revoke your previously provided consent, review information collected from your child or have that information deleted, please contact us via the options in Section 12: Contact Us. If we become aware that a child has provided us with personal information without parental consent, we will delete any personal information we have collected, unless we have a legal obligation to keep it, and terminate the child's account and/or revert them to the age-appropriate experience, as applicable.  
  
If we make material changes to how we collect, use, share or otherwise process your child's personal information, we will notify parents as required by applicable law.  
  
We encourage you to talk with your children about communicating with strangers and the risks of disclosing personal information online. You and your child should review the privacy settings applicable to their use of our Services, a summary of which is available on our Player and Parental Tools page: https://www.ea.com/commitments/positive-play/parental-controls.  
  
8\. Your Choices and Controls  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: We provide you with choice and control about our use of your information, including your ability to exercise your data privacy rights.  
\------------------------------------  
  
We give you meaningful choices when it comes to our collection and use of your information. For example, if you no longer want to receive marketing emails from EA, you may click the unsubscribe link included in the footer of any marketing email we send.  
  
You can learn how to exercise any of your privacy rights by visiting our My Privacy Rights portal: https://www.ea.com/legal/privacy-portal.  
  
We offer the rights below as provided by applicable law in the countries and jurisdictions in which we offer our Services. These laws include the General Data Protection Regulation (GDPR) in the European Union, and state privacy laws enacted in the United States. While we provide additional details where necessary to comply with jurisdiction-specific legal requirements, such as in our section on Information for California Residents, these details are illustrative and not intended to limit similar rights that may be available elsewhere.  
  
You may appeal our decision regarding your privacy rights. To do so, please visit our My Privacy Rights portal (https://www.ea.com/legal/privacy-portal#sectionOther) and click on "Other privacy enquiries".  
  
Verification of account ownership. To protect your account security and personal information, you may be asked to verify your account ownership prior to us processing your request to exercise your data privacy rights. Verification methods include being logged into your EA Account, confirming ownership and access to the email address associated with your account, and/or confirming other unique account details.  
  
Authorized agents. You can use an authorized agent to make a request to exercise your data privacy rights. Please contact us at EA Help (help.ea.com) to initiate that request. If you use an authorized agent to exercise your right to deletion, access, or correction, we will require that you verify your account ownership directly with us, unless you have provided your agent with a valid power of attorney consistent with California law that includes a comparable proof of account ownership.  
  
If you use an authorized agent to submit a request to opt-out of the sale or sharing of your personal information for targeted marketing purposes, we will require your signed permission demonstrating that you have authorized the agent to act on your behalf.  
  
Your right to deletion. You may deactivate your EA Account or delete the personal information associated with your account by contacting us at EA Help (help.ea.com). If you do so, you will no longer have access to the EA games or Services associated with your account. Note that EA may retain information needed to resolve disputes, enforce our user agreements, protect our legal rights, and comply with technical and legal requirements and constraints related to the security, integrity and operation of our Services. Otherwise, we will retain your personal information for as long as reasonably necessary to provide you with, create, and improve our Services, and to comply with the law.  
  
Your right to access (or "know"). You can access the personal information we hold about you, including the categories of personal information collected, where we collect it from, why and how we use it, and who may receive this information (including to whom it may be sold or shared, as those terms are defined under applicable law). The generally applicable details about our processing are provided in this Policy. With respect to the information specific to our processing of your information, you can download a copy of your EA Account information by visiting your EA Account (https://myaccount.ea.com/cp-ui/downloaddata/index) and clicking the "Your EA Data" tab. To receive further details, please contact us at EA Help (help.ea.com).  
  
Your right to correction. You can request correction of your personal information where it is inaccurate. In some cases, we may provide self-service tools, such as those on the EA Account customer portal, that enable you to update some of your personal information: https://myaccount.ea.com/cp-ui/aboutme/index.  
  
Your right to opt-out or object to certain processing. You may opt-out of targeted advertising, or object to processing of your data based on our legitimate interests, where applicable law provides for such rights. This right is also referred to as the ability to opt-out of the sale or sharing of your personal information, as specifically provided by applicable US state privacy laws. To exercise these rights, please see further instructions in our My Privacy Rights portal (https://www.ea.com/legal/privacy-portal), including the Targeted Advertising Provided by Third Parties section.  
  
Cookie Controls. If you are in a location whose laws may require additional choices, you can control cookies and similar technologies used on most EA sites for certain optional functional and advertising analytics and targeted advertising purposes via the banner that appears at the bottom of the webpage during your first visit. You can also disable some cookies, limit the types of cookies you allow, or set your browser to alert you when cookies are being sent. Please refer to guidance provided by your individual web browser if you'd like help in managing your cookie preferences.  
  
The effect of your choice will depend on the context in which you exercise it:  
  
\- If you opt-out of having your information shared for purposes of targeted advertising on PC and console through your EA Account, your choice will take effect for any PC and console games that you have logged into with your EA Account.  
\- If you opt-out of having your information shared for purposes of targeted advertising through one of our mobile game settings, your choice will take effect for that mobile game.  
\- If you opt-out of having your information shared for purposes of web targeted advertising through our cookies controls, your choice will take effect when visiting our websites through the browser and device on which you made that choice.  
  
Global Privacy Control. In certain regions, we recognize an opt-out preference signal sent by your web browser (sometimes referred to as the Global Privacy Control or "GPC") as a valid request to opt-out of the sale and sharing of the personal information processed via the browser you are using. In practice this controls whether your browser loads third-party cookies on our Services' websites that are used for targeted advertising, or may otherwise be considered a sale or sharing of personal information. We process this signal only based on browser settings, so you would need to set them separately for different browsers on the same device and across devices. Please review the list of browsers that support GPC and associated instructions (https://globalprivacycontrol.org/#download) on how to enable it. GPC does not control targeted advertising in our PC, console, or mobile games and must be changed via your account or the game's settings, as described above.  
  
You have a right not to receive discriminatory treatment for the exercise of these privacy rights.  
  
9\. Third-Party Services  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: Our websites and Services may contain ads or links to third-party services and sites.  
\------------------------------------  
  
Our websites and Services may contain advertising or links to third-party services (such as the Facebook "Like" button or links to third-party websites). If you click on those links, including an advertisement, you will leave the EA Service and go to the third-party service or site that you selected. If you visit a third-party website or use a third-party service, you should consult that service's or site's privacy policy as your use of third-party sites or services is governed by their privacy policies.  
  
10\. Information for California Residents  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: California law requires certain additional disclosures about how we process your personal information.  
\------------------------------------  
  
A. Notice at Collection  
  
Depending on your use of our Services, the following categories of personal information may have been collected and disclosed in the preceding 12 months, as these categories are defined under the California Consumer Privacy Act ("CCPA"):  
  
\- Identifiers; such as a real name, user name, account name, email, online identifiers, device identifiers, IP address, or mobile device identifiers;  
\- Account login data; we collect and process the credentials necessary for you to access your EA Account; for any third-party connected accounts, following your authorization, we collect an access token that allows us to receive information from that third-party specific to your account with them;  
\- Purchase information; such as payment card number, payment account details, billing address, and other payment information;  
\- Characteristics of Protected Classifications under state or federal law; such as age or gender;  
\- Commercial Information; such as products or services interaction and purchase history;  
\- Internet or Electronic Network Activity information; such as, browsing history, search history, and information regarding interactions with our games, websites, applications, and/or advertisements;  
\- Approximate (coarse) geolocation data; such as location data derived from IP address or device settings;  
\- Audio or Electronic information; such as when you play our games, play certain multiplayer modes, use chat features, or participate in competitive game modes or live events;  
\- Contents of players' in-game messaging;  
\- Inferences; such as consumer preferences drawn from the above.  
  
In certain circumstances, we may also collect and disclose additional information, such as:  
  
\- If you are the recipient of a contest or sweepstakes prize that requires tax reporting, we may collect identifiers associated with your government-issued documents (such as a social security number).  
\- If you participate in our competitive gaming events, we may collect identifiers associated with your government-issued documents (such as a passport number), financial information (such as bank accounts), and health-related information.  
\- If you participate in our user experience research, we may collect financial information (such as bank accounts), health-related information and video footage of your gameplay, as well as your recorded image throughout the session.  
  
We may collect and disclose other categories of personal information to the extent that you provide them through in-game chat, forums, or through our player support channels.  
  
Collection, use, and disclosure of this information is made for one or more of the business or commercial purposes listed in Section 3: How We Use Your Information.  
  
The following categories of personal information may be "sold" or "shared," as those terms are defined under the CCPA, for purposes of targeted advertising:  
  
\- Identifiers; such as a real name, user name, account name, email, online identifiers, device identifiers, IP address, or mobile device identifiers;  
\- Characteristics of Protected Classifications under state or federal law; such as age or gender;  
\- Commercial Information; such as products or services interaction and purchase history;  
\- Internet or Electronic Network Activity information; such as, browsing history, search history, and information regarding interactions with our games, websites, applications, and/or advertisements;  
\- Approximate (coarse) geolocation data; such as location data derived from IP address or device settings;  
\- Audio or Electronic information; such as when you play our games, play certain multiplayer modes, use chat features, or participate in competitive game modes or live events;  
\- Inferences; such as consumer preferences drawn from the above.  
  
This information may have been sold or shared with our advertising partners for the purposes described in the respective paragraph of Section 4: Who May Receive Your Information.  
  
We do not "sell" or "share," as those terms are defined under the CCPA, personal information of consumers under 16 years of age. We also only use or disclose "sensitive personal information," as defined under the CCPA, for the purposes specified in Section 7027(m) of the California Consumer Privacy Act Regulations (https://cppa.ca.gov/regulations/pdf/cppa\_regs.pdf).  
  
We retain the information we collect for as long as necessary to provide our Services, and we may retain that information beyond that period if necessary for legal, operational, or other legitimate reasons.  
  
Please review Your Choices (https://www.ea.com/legal/privacy-portal) related to the sale and sharing of your personal information for cross-context behavioral advertising purposes (also known as targeted advertising).  
  
For additional details, please review our overall Privacy and Cookie Policy: https://tos.ea.com/legalapp/WEBPRIVACY/US/en/pc2/.  
  
B. Supplemental California Privacy Notice  
  
Please see below for more details about how we process your personal information, incorporating the notice immediately above.  
  
For each of the categories of personal information referenced above:  
  
\- The categories of sources from which the personal information may have been collected are listed in Section 1: Information We Collect.  
\- The categories of third-party recipients to which the personal information may be disclosed are listed in Section 4: Who May Receive Your Information.  
  
C. Your Rights  
  
Please see Section 8: Your Choices and Controls for a summary of your California privacy rights and how to exercise them. This includes the right to opt-out of the sale or sharing of your personal information for cross-context behavioral advertising purposes (also known as targeted advertising), as further described in the subsection regarding Your right to opt-out or object to certain processing.  
  
11\. Changes to Our Policy  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: This policy will be updated from time to time and we will notify you of material changes.  
\------------------------------------  
  
We may occasionally update this privacy policy. When we do, we will revise the "last updated" date at the bottom of the policy. If there are material changes to this policy, we will use reasonable efforts to notify you either by prominently posting a notice of such changes before they take effect or by directly sending you a notification.  
  
12\. Contact Us  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: You may contact us if you have questions about this policy.  
\------------------------------------  
  
If you have questions about this policy, please use our My Privacy Rights portal to contact our Data Protection Officer: https://www.ea.com/legal/privacy-portal.  
  
To contact EA, including our Data Protection Officer, you can also use the following address: Electronic Arts Inc., 209 Redwood Shores Parkway, Redwood City, CA 94065. Electronic Arts Inc.'s representative in the European Union is Electronic Arts Ireland Limited, Parkmore West Business Park, 1, Ballybrit, Galway, H91 Y2R5, Ireland. Electronic Arts Inc.'s representative in the United Kingdom is Electronic Arts Limited, Onslow House, Onslow Street, Guildford, GU1 4TN, United Kingdom.  
  
13\. Right to Contact a Data Protection Authority  
\------------------------------------  
SECTION SUMMARY: You may have the right to contact your Data Protection Authority.  
\------------------------------------  
  
If you have a concern about how we collect and use information, please contact us. You also have the right to contact your local Data Protection Authority if you prefer, such as:  
  
\- Data Protection Authorities in the EEA: https://edpb.europa.eu/about-edpb/board/members\_en;  
\- Swiss authorities: https://www.edoeb.admin.ch/edoeb/en/home/deredoeb/kontakt.html;  
\- UK authority: https://ico.org.uk/global/contact-us/.  
  
Where appropriate, your local data protection authority may also forward the matter to the Department of Commerce or FTC for consideration.  
  
If you have an unresolved concern over our data practices that we have not addressed satisfactorily, please contact our U.S.-based third-party dispute resolution provider (free of charge): https://feedback-form.truste.com/watchdog/request.  

Last Updated: August 23, 2024
